Andy del Valle

Seattle, WA | 661-319-4385 | andydelvalle89@gmail.com Github: andydvalle | Blog: Medium | Portfolio | LinkedIn

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a nursing background who enjoys being at the intersection of logic and creativity to design dynamic websites with a systematic approach. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React based programming. Previous healthcare and customer service experience allows me to bring strong skills in critical thinking, interpersonal communication, and project management that help companies deliver satisfying user interfaces and experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, JavaScript, React, Hooks, SQL, Postgres, JSON, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Simple Care - Github | Video Demo | Live Demo

Medical care app to help caregivers manage their loved ones medications, health conditions, appointments, and clinics

- Developed backend and frontend to organize medical care using Ruby on Rails and React components
- Utilized JSON web tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Leveraged the National Library of Medicine API to create an autocomplete search table using CSS and React Hooks
- Implemented the design ideas of and collaborated with a UX Designer through Figma to improve user experience

Message In a Bottle - Github | Video Demo | Live Demo

Mental Health/Journal app that allows users to anonymously send or receive messages to other writers around the world

- Created API with Ruby on Rails and Active Record for data persistence of messages, journals, and users
- Utilized Postgres to design database schema and coded database logic
- Designed frontend styling with Bootstrap and CSS for an elegant design to optimize user experience and navigation

Seattle Bike Traffic- Github | Video Demo

Biking app that provides bike counter data allowing cyclists to visualize route information with relative graphs and reviews

- Used Socrata Open Data API using JSON to render monthly bike counter data into a line graph
- Built the comments feature using Ruby on Rails and ActiveRecord to associate them with specific bike counters
- Collaborated in a team setting that applied Gitflow to create multiple pull requests with each new feature

EXPERIENCE

Highline Medical Center

Registered Nurse, Intensive Care Unit

Seattle, WA

11/2018 - 03/2020

- Cared for patients with life-threatening conditions and delivered medical interventions ordered by physician
- Handled critical care equipment such as ventilators, IV pumps, bedside monitors, and cooling machines
- Titrated continuous infusions and administered medications after calculating proper dosage based on assessments
- Charted nursing notes, vital signs, and interventions on EPIC, a cloud-based electronic health record

Kern Medical Center Bakersfield, CA 01/2018 - 10/2018

Hospital Staff Nurse I. Intensive Care Unit

- Adhered to best practices and strict hospital protocols set by evidenced based research
- Calculated correct dosage and administered medications after doing safety checks
- Used MediTech, an electronic medical record system

Aira Tech Corp (remote)

San Diego, CA

Aira Agent

05/2017 - 02/2018

- Provided visual information to blind and visually impaired clients via Aira smart glasses/phone camera
- Used orientation and mobility terminology to help clients navigate their surroundings

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Seattle, WA 04/2020 - 07/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Bakersfield, CA

Bakersfield College

Associate Degree, Registered Nursing

12/2017